PAUL WABUGE KALENDA

CONTACT

P.O BOX 105068-00101 Nairobi, Kenya

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with 2+ years of experience as an engineer who is passionate about solving problems using technology and also taking up new challenges. I am a team player recognized for creative ideas and a

passionate approach. I have experience working in an agile team utilizing agile product development process. Also, I approach product development using tests driven development approach. My core expertise lies in Javascript, Java language and Spring frameworks. I am a fast-paced learner and open to learning new technology

WORK EXPERIENCE

BSK Global Technologies, Nairobi

May 2020 — Present

E-mail: kpaul7747@gmail.com

Phone: (+254) 715 668 934

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Main Responsibilities:

- Execute full lifecycle software development
- Deploy and Maintain new software applications
- Help write and modify well designed, testable, efficient code
- Understand and support existing systems
- Code maintenance and bug fixing
- Integrate software components into a fully functional software system
- Contribute to technical architecture sessions and lead efforts to build and maintain a highly scalable software platform
- Participate in system manual creation and code documentation

Achievement Highlights:

I take part in developing enterprise systems among others. While working on the projects, I am able to optimise database performance by indexing the tables. This resulted in site loading faster and better search experience to the users of the system. I am also able to save logs into the database for every process on the system. This resulted in easy maintenance of the system to the support team as they have all the details into a database of what went wrong. Hence they are able to solve the arising issues first. I am able to review teammates codes and advise better ways of handling exceptions which reduced site downtimes and make the system more stable.

Dew CIS Solutions Ltd, Nairobi

JAN 2020 — April 2020

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AND TECHNICAL SUPPORT

Day to day activities involved the planning and development of websites and web applications. I also give IT support to customers in the form of training on the utilization of their website or web application and resolve technical issues. Some of the technologies used in web application development include Baraza frame work, Git, Linux server. I successfully increased customers' satisfaction with the improved technical support I provided.

PALIE WARLIGE KALENDA

Achievement Highlights:

- Contributed to an open-source Baraza project Like SMS, Attendance using java, Suprema's products and softwares.
- worked on search, text highlight, and comment, reaction functionalities. Etc
- Contributed to both frontend and backend feature.
- Contributed to internal products using Java, javascript and Android.
- Designed and developed web applications from the planning stage to the development stage. e.g Wolenge Africa.
- I improved some existing source codes by ensuring clean and efficient systems.

Dew CIS Solutions Ltd, Nairobi March 2018 — September 2018 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AND TECHNICAL SUPPORT

Day to day activities involved the planning and development of web applications. I also give IT support to customers in the form of training on the utilization of their web application and resolve technical issues. Some of the technologies used in web application development include Baraza frame work, Suprema's products and softwares, JAVA, Git, Linux server. I successfully increased customers' satisfaction with the improved technical support I provided.

Achievement Highlights:

- Contributed to an open-source Baraza project Like Attendance using java, Suprema's products and softwares.
- Designed and developed Biometrics applications from the planning stage to the development stage.
- Learned new technology within a short span and successfully redeveloped an application template to serve an original purpose.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science In Informatics

September 2015 — December 2019

Moi University

Informatics is the science of information, the practice of information processing, and the engineering of information systems. Informatics studies the structure, algorithms, behavior, and interactions of natural and artificial systems that store, process, access and communicate information. Informatics can also be considered as a bridging discipline that is fundamentally interested in the application of information, information technology and information systems within organisations.

SKILLS

- Java(Excellent)
- Kotlin(Excellent)
- Angular (Excellent),
- React (Excellent),
- Javascript (Excellent),
- Spring Boot(Excellent),
- Docker (Excellent),
- Postgres (Excellent),
- Android Studio(Good),
- OracleSql(Good),
- TypeScript(Good),
- XML(Good)

PAUL WARLIGE KALENDA

- Agile Software Development
- Strong collaboration skills
- Status tracking tools (Jira)

REFERENCES

Name: Mr. Dennis Gichangi, Company: Dew CIS Solution,

Position: Ltd Director, Department of Software Developing,

Email: dennis.gichangi@dewcis.com,

Phone: +254 733 578 156.

Name: James Mantu, Company: Microsoft,

Position: Senior Program Manager,

Email:,

Phone: +254 722 242 040.

PAUL WABUGE KALENDA